Guide to the Creative Time Records MSS.179
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Grants and Development, 1974-2007; 37.74 Linear Feet in 14 record cartons, 10 manuscript boxes, 6 box binders, 20 jewel cases, 6 oversized folders, and 1 flat box; 95 kilobytes in 7 computer files; 6 CDs; 10 DVD-R; 3 DVDs; 3 VHS; 4 U-matic; 3 Hi8
  - 20th Anniversary Celebration -- Apollo Theater, July 1994
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Tape 1 (Box 148, Cd 179.0392)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Tape 2 (Box 148, Cd 179.0394)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Tape 1 (Box Shared Fales 103, Folder ID: 179.0394)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Tape 2 (Box Shared Fales 103, Folder ID: 179.0395)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- "7/7/94" -- Tape 1 of 2 (Box 151, Dvd 179.0609)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- "7/7/94" -- Tape 2 of 2 (Box 148, Dvd 179.0364)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- "7/7/94" -- Tape 3 (Box 148, Dvd 179.0396)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Interviews (Box 149, Dvd 179.0485)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- "Creative Time: 20 Years of Art in Unexpected Places" (Box Shared Fales 146, Dvd 179.0738)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Dyke TV -- "20 Years of Art in Unexpected Places" (Box 148, Dvd 179.0358)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Dyke TV -- "20 Years of Art in Unexpected Places" (Box 149, Dvd 179.0431)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Tape 1 of 2 (Box Shared Fales 146, Dvd 179.0741)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Tape 2 of 2 (Box Shared Fales 146, Dvd 179.0744)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- "7/7/94" -- Tape 1 of 2 (Box 31, Folder ID: 179.0608)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- "7/7/94" -- Tape 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0363)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- "7/7/94" -- Tape 3 (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0395)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Interviews (Box 28, Folder ID: 179.0484)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Dyke TV -- "20 Years of Art in Unexpected Places" (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0357)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Dyke TV -- "20 Years of Art in Unexpected Places" (Box 28, Folder ID: 179.0430)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Tape 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0391)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Tape 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0393)
  - Valentine's Party and Temporary Tattoo Kits, February 1996 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Holiday Shopping Tours, November 1996 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Exquisite Corpse -- Fashion Kick-Off Benefit, September 1997
    - Invitations, Programs, and Press (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Slides (Box 126, Folder Sleeve 26)
  - Sponsorship Appeals, 1998-2000
    - Electronic Records, cuid40929
    - Correspondence (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Benefit -- Slides, 2001 (Box 130, Folder Sleeve 21)
  - Winter in the Fall Benefit, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 249, Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Liars, The Rogers Sisters, and Blood on the Wall: Benefit for Creative Time, December 2003 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Burlesque Bash, March 2004
    - Invitation and Correspondence (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Burlesque Video -- 2 Versions (Box 149, Dvd 179.0433)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Burlesque Video -- 2 Versions (Box 28, Folder ID: 179.0432)
  - Trip the Light Fantastic Benefit, 2005
    - Correspondence, Programs, and Invitations (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Slides (Box 131, Folder Sleeve 32)
  - Shirin Neshat Benefit, 2006 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - 33rd Anniversary Benefit, 2007; cuid40930 (Box 89, Folder 12)
- Series III. Administrative Materials, 1974-2007; 28.83 Linear Feet in 11 record cartons, 9 manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes, and 27 jewel cases; 116 kilobytes in 1 computer file; 13 CDs; 13 DVD-R; 3 DVDs; 6 VHS; 7 MiniDV
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, with the exception of materials on the history of the organization first and general correspondence last.
  This series consists of historical information (early brochures with mission statements); annual reports (catalogues with summaries of the organization's yearly exhibitions and projects); materials on art education projects, such as working with the University Settlement House's youth on Duston Spear's That Big Yellow Braid in 1997; certificates received by the organization; statements and responses by the organization regarding issues in the arts (such as Mayor Giuliani's censorship of a Brooklyn Museum exhibition in 1999); conference and symposia programs in which Creative Time staff participated; interviews with staff; press clippings and press releases on the organization and its staff; staff and board meeting minutes and internal correspondence; documentation of the organization's possible merger with Thread Waxing Space, another arts organization based in New York City, which was not realized; and general office correspondence. These materials reflect the growth of Creative Time and the daily administrative tasks undertaken by various staff members to support the organization's various projects.
  - History of Creative Time, circa 1974-1995
    - Correspondence and Biographical Information (Box 1, Folder 4, Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Negatives, Contact Sheets, and Prints (Box 19, Folder 10-12)
  - Advocacy Actions, 1989-2005
    - Electronic Records, cuid40893
    - Correspondence, Press, Flyers, and Photographs (Box 3, Folder 132-133, Folder 143-144, Box 4, Folder 191, Box 90, Folder 2-3)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- "Living With AIDS: Seize Control of the FDA" (Box 150, Dvd 179.0523)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- "Living With AIDS: Seize Control of the FDA" (Box 29, Folder ID: 179.0522)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Bravo -- "Unfinished Stories" -- Presentation Tape (Box 30, Folder ID: 179.0667)
  - Annual Reports/Catalogues, 1974-1994 (Box 2, Folder 85, Box 3, Folder 119, Box 4, Folder 171, Folder 211, Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Art Education Projects and Proposals, 1994-1998 (Box 90, Folder 5-6)
  - Certificate of Merit from Municipal Art Society of New York, June 1997 (Box 91, Folder 1, Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Conference and Symposium Participation, 1994-2003
    - Correspondence, Programs, and Press (Box 91, Folder 2-3)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Artist Roundtable -- Final Group Discussion, August 2003 (Box 145, Dvd 179.0136)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Artist Roundtable -- Vardit's Group, August 2003 (Box 145, Dvd 179.0150)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Artist Roundtable -- Carol's Group, August 2003 (Box 151, Dvd 179.0639)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Artist Roundtable -- Vardit, August 2003 (Box 150, Dvd 179.0503)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Focus Group -- 1 of 2, March 2003 (Box 151, Dvd 179.0643)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Focus Group -- 2 of 2, March 2003 (Box 151, Dvd 179.0645)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Artist Roundtable -- Final Group Discussion, August 2003 (Box 26, Folder ID: 179.0135)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Artist Roundtable -- Vardit's Group, August 2003 (Box 26, Folder ID: 179.0149)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Artist Roundtable -- Carol's Group, August 2003 (Box 31, Folder ID: 179.0638)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Artist Roundtable -- Vardit, August 2003 (Box 29, Folder ID: 179.0502)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Focus Group -- 1 of 2, March 2003 (Box 31, Folder ID: 179.0642)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Focus Group -- 2 of 2, March 2003 (Box 31, Folder ID: 179.0644)
  - Interviews with Staff, 2001
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Anne Pasternak -- "On World Trade Center Response" (Box 144, Cd 179.0018)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Anne Pasternak -- General (Box 144, Cd 179.0020)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Kevin McHugh (Box 144, Cd 179.0022)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Carol Stakenas (Box 144, Cd 179.0012)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Elizabeth Iarrappino (Box Shared Fales 147, Cd 179.0002)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Kelly Evans (Box Shared Fales 147, Cd 179.0008)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Harriet Senie (Box Shared Fales 147, Cd 179.0006)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Rachel Stevens (Box 144, Cd 179.0014)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Sarah Bacon (Box 144, Cd 179.0016)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Anita Contini -- Artists' Space -- Christian Science Monitor -- Cut #4 (Box 145, Cd 179.0092)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Anne Pasternak -- "On World Trade Center Response" (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0017)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Anne Pasternak -- General (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0019)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Kevin McHugh (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0021)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Carol Stakenas (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0011)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Elizabeth Iarrappino (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0001)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Kelly Evans (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0007)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Harriet Senie (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0005)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Rachel Stevens (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0013)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Sarah Bacon (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0015)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Anita Contini -- Artists' Space -- Christian Science Monitor -- Cut #4 (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0091)
  - Press and Publicity, 1980-2006
    - Press Releases, Clippings, and Articles (Box 2, Folder 55, Folder 77, Box 3, Folder 139, Box 4, Folder 168, Folder 184, Box 5, Folder 238, Box 91, Folder 4-5)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Jeremy Dawson and Richard Gordon -- Creative Time Commercial Loop, November 1998 (Box 148, Dvd 179.0390)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Jeremy Dawson and Richard Gordon -- Creative Time Commercial, November 1998 (Box 148, Dvd 179.0409)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Jeremy Dawson and Richard Gordon -- Creative Time Commercial Loop, November 1998 (Box 148, Dvd 179.0388)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Show Reel -- Leap, Tribute in Light, Tap, and 59th Minute, 2000-2002 (Box 148, Dvd 179.0419)
    - Video Recording -- Access Copy -- Anne Pasternak and Stephanie Simon, February 2005 (Box 147, Dvd 179.0270)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Jeremy Dawson and Richard Gordon -- Creative Time Commercial Loop, November 1998 (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0389)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Jeremy Dawson and Richard Gordon -- Creative Time Commercial, November 1998 (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0408)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Jeremy Dawson and Richard Gordon -- Creative Time Commercial Loop (Box 27, Folder ID: 179.0387)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Show Reel -- Leap, Tribute in Light, Tap, and 59th Minute (Box 28, Folder ID: 179.0418)
    - Video Recording -- Original -- Anne Pasternak and Stephanie Simon, February 2005 (Box 25, Folder ID: 179.0269)
  - Staff and Board Meetings, 1991-2006
    - Meeting Minutes and Correspondence (Box 91, Folder 6, Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Board Meeting -- Part 1, September 1993 (Box 145, Cd 179.0083)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Board Meeting -- Part 2, September 1993 (Box 145, Cd 179.0084)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Memorial Discussion -- New York University -- 1 of 2, March 2002 (Box 145, Cd 179.0097)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Memorial Discussion -- New York University -- 2 of 2, March 2002 (Box 145, Cd 179.0098)
    - Audio Recording -- Access Copy -- Rachel Stevens -- NAAMP Portfolio Presentation, December 2001 (Box 149, Cd 179.0429)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Board Meeting, September 1993 (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0082)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Memorial Discussion -- New York University -- 1 of 2, March 2002 (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0095)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Memorial Discussion -- New York University -- 2 of 2, March 2002 (Box 33, Folder ID: 179.0049)
    - Audio Recording -- Original -- Rachel Stevens -- NAAMP Portfolio Presentation, December 2001 (Box 28, Folder ID: 179.0428)
  - Thread Waxing Space Merger -- Unrealized, 2000 (Box 92, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1980 (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1981 (Box 142, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1983-1994 (Box 143, Folder 4, Box 2, Folder 75, Folder 93, Folder 101, Box 3, Folder 117-118, Folder 138, Box 4, Folder 170, Folder 192, Folder 210, Folder 213, Box 92, Box 5, Folder 240)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1995 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1996 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1997 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1998 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1999-2001 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- General, 2002 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- General, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 251, Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- General, 2004 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- General, 2005 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- General, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 256, Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- General, 2007 (Box 94, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Archived Websites, March 2009, May 2020-ongoing; 13 websites in 13 archived websites.
  This series contains the main website for Creative Time, as well as its subdomains. The website is made up of a listing of all of their projects dating back to 1974. Each project page can contain an overview of the artwork, a biography of the artist, visitor information, images and/or video of the work, digital platforms of the art, curatorial statements, press about the project, contextual resources, guides or syllabi associated with the work, and public events surrounding the work. The website also features a blog with news from the arts organization, event listings at CTHQ, and information on the Creative Time Summit. The website also documents their projects in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Their web presence also includes projects related to the Creative Time Think Tank and other 50th anniversary celebrations in 2021.
  The series also includes multiple digital publications, including their two Tumblr blogs and Creative Time Reports (2012-2017). Creative Time Reports focused on political analysis, commentary, op-eds, podcasts, photo galleries, and videos from the artists' perspective. Topics covered in Reports include civil liberties, climate change, conflict zones, the economy, elections, feminism, LGBTQIA+ rights, migration, incarceration, race, and uprisings.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of creativetime.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Website was rescoped to attempt to capture the Google documents in the website.